《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
怪物要来了  市长先生
Monsters are coming, Mr. Mayor.
六名精神病罪犯被劫狱逃离了阿卡姆疯人院
Six criminally insane inmates were busted out of Arkham Asylum.
他们要大众惶恐
They want mass panic.
吉姆
Hello, Jim.
我看上去如何
How do I look?
芭芭拉
Barbara!
局长
Yo, Commish.
嗯
Yeah?
别动
Don't move!
你还是赶紧回单位吧
You should probably get back to work.
谁知道你不在时出了什么乱子呢
Who knows what went wrong while you were gone?
是新的一天  吉姆
It's a new day Jim.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 夜影章鱼X   盐湖凉开水   charcie   Silence
翻译 艾瑞卡   小酸奶!   precise小姐   DustD   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
杰罗姆·瓦勒斯卡
Jerome Valeska.
针对哥谭市警局的袭击
The attack on the GCPD.
肯定有人透露内情
Someone on the streets is talking.
肯定有人知道什么
Somebody knows something.
瓦勒斯卡一头红发  笑声疯狂
Valeska has red hair, crazy laugh.
可能跟一个金发妞一起出没
Might be rolling with a blonde number.
我什么都不知道
I-I don't know anything.
-真不知道  -你信他吗
- Honest! - You believe him?
信个鬼
Nope.
我也不信
Me neither.
我真的不知道  不过
It's the truth! But, hey,
我可以帮你们  散播风声什么的
I-I can help you guys, you know, spread the word and stuff.
瓦勒斯卡杀了我们的朋友
Valeska killed a friend of ours.
任何藏匿他的人
Anybody hides him,
任何保护他的人
anybody protects him,
都死定了  听见了吗
they go down, too, you got it?
出去传吧
Now spread the word.
不  不
No! No!
哥谭
第二季  第三集
要偷偷溜走吗
Sneaking out?
跟男人一个样
Just like a guy.
还有事情要了结
There are loose ends that need tying.
要用这个吗
Need this?
带百吉饼回来哦
Bring back bagels.
那倒不用了
No need for that.
我正好想和基恩小姐好好聊聊
I thought Ms. Kean and I could have a little chat.
早上好
Good morning.
杰罗姆在外边等着呢
Jerome is waiting outside.
让他专注些
Try and keep him focused.
你客气点
You be nice.
你俩似乎挺合得来啊
You two seem to be getting along.
我真高兴
I'm so glad.
她需要朋友
She needs a friend.
我妹妹是个很特别的人
My sister is a very special person.
她看似很坚强  其实内心脆弱得很
She seems so strong, but yet she's quite fragile.
加糖吗
Sugar?
好啊
Sure.
这趟哥谭市警局的大冒险
You acquitted yourself very well
你表现得很好啊
at the adventure at the GCPD.
吉姆·戈登毫发无伤地躲过了屠杀
Jim Gordon escaped the carnage unscathed.
太漂亮了
Top marks.
多谢
Thank you.
你知道是我们家建了这座城市吗
Did you know my family built this city?
是我们切好了本市的基石
We carved the bedrock upon which it stands,
但满城街桥道巷上
yet there is not a bridge, an alley,
却没有我们的名字
a ditch that carries our name.
我的先辈遭到了背叛  他们的功绩被抹除
My forefathers were betrayed, their legacy erased,
而我就是要惩罚那些背叛者
and I am here to punish those who wronged us
重夺家族荣光
and reclaim what is ours.
加草莓酱吗
Strawberry?
抱歉我自作主张了
I didn't ask.
所以你打算靠放出几个疯子
So you're gonna take over Gotham
来夺取哥谭
by unleashing a bunch of loonies.
算盘打得不错
Awesome plan.
这只是计划的第一步
That's only part one.
那第二步是什么
So what's the second part?
你肯定会喜欢的
You're gonna love it.
你要扮演主角呢
There's a starring role for you.
你会有名有势
You'll be famous and powerful,
你最大的梦想也会成真
and your fondest dream will come true.
你知道我的梦想  是吗
You know my dreams, do you?
等吉姆·戈登没用了
When Jim Gordon has outlived his usefulness,
我会帮你毁灭他
I'm gonna help you destroy him.
不是杀了他
Not kill him.
而是彻底毁灭他
Destroy him.
从肉体到灵魂
Body and soul.
令人震惊的画面  哥谭处于高度警戒之中...
Shocking images. Gotham is on high alert today after...
我只是说  我乐意把那些讨厌鬼
Look, I'm just saying, I'll chuck mopes out of windows
一个个丢出窗外  但终归
until the cows come home, but at some point,
我们得去见企鹅
we got to go see Penguin.
他为什么要帮杰罗姆从阿卡姆越狱
Why would he break Jerome out of Arkham
并袭击哥谭市警局呢
or attack the GCPD?
他不会这样做  但现在那混蛋是老大了
He wouldn't, but that weasel's running things now.
-有风吹草动  他就会知道  -我会考虑的
- If there's chatter, he'd know it. - I'll think about it.
-吉姆  -我说会考虑的
- Jim... - I'll think about it!
阿尔瓦雷斯  杰罗姆的马戏团熟人查怎么样了
Alvarez, where are you with Jerome's circus contacts?
马戏团在州北呢  我正在等...
Circus is upstate. I'm just waiting...
跟进
Follow up.
他可能跟父亲在一起呢  他以前就保护过他
His father's probably with him. He covered for him once before.
他可能知道消息
He might have some information.
去吧  警探
Do it. Yo, Detective!
你在追踪哪个逃犯
Which escapee are you tracking?
赫尔辛格  没人见过他
Helzinger. No one's seen him.
他一米八  250斤
He's six-seven, 275,
却只有五岁孩子的智商
with the mind of a five-year-old.
肯定有人见过他的
Somebody's seen him.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我们抓到凶手前  别动那个
That stays up until we have her killer in custody.
-明白吗  -是  长官
- You understand? - Yes, sir.
莎拉·艾森和另外九个弟兄
Sarah Essen and nine of your brothers
就在这里被杀
were killed in this house.
在我们的地盘上
In our house!
杀死他们的人曾站在这里  还嘲笑我们
Their murderer stood right there, and he laughed at us.
永远不要忘记
Never forget that.
干什么
What?!
你还好吗
So how are you?
我没事
I'm fine.
真的吗
Really?
我知道艾森是你的朋友
Look, I know Essen was your friend.
小莱  不管你要说什么
Lee, whatever you're about to say,
我知道你是出于好意
I know it's coming from a good place,
但我现在听不进去
but I can't hear it right now.
哥谭儿童医院晚会就在今晚
So, the Gotham Children's Hospital gala is tonight,
我有帮忙策划哦
which I helped organize.
不行
I can't.
-你不能去吗  -不行
- You can't go? - No.
即便几小时的清净
Even though a few hours away from all of this
会对你有好处
might actually help?
小莱
Lee.
好吧  那有件事我得告诉你
Okay. I just have to tell you something,
如果我不说  等你发现了
because if I don't and you find out,
你会很生气的
you're gonna be pissed.
会有魔术师到场哦
There's gonna be a magician.
嗯  好吧
Yeah. Right.
别自责了
Stop beating yourself up.
-我在尽力  -我知道
- I'm trying. - I know you are.
我本该在场的  但我没在
I should have been here. I wasn't.
打住
Stop it.
亲我
Kiss me.
好点了吗
Better?
无意打扰你俩时机不当的亲热
Not to interrupt your weirdly timed make-out session,
阿尔瓦雷斯联系上了马戏团经理
but Alvarez got in touch with the circus manager.
那个算命瞎子  杰罗姆的老爸
The blind fortune teller, Jerome's dad,
放弃了他  后来留在城里
bailed on him, stayed in town.
查到他地址了
Got an address.
-回头打给你  -好
- I'll call you. - Okay.
谁
Who's there?
我知道有人在
I know someone's there.
好呀  老爹
Hi-ya, Pops.
好久...不见
Long time... no see.
你还好吗
So, how you doing?
不说话是吧
The silent treatment, eh?
这样  我给你讲个故事
Here, I'll tell you a story.
你还记得堪萨斯城吗  老爸
You remember Kansas City, Dad?
每年春天我生日期间
The circus went through town every spring
马戏团都去城里巡演
right around my birthday.
有个男人
There was this guy.
他和我妈常常喝酒私通
Him and my mom used to drink and fornicate
还把我打得半死
and beat the crap out of me.
他俩能这么疯一整晚
They'd make a whole night out of it.
我记得有一次
And I remember one time--
那是我九岁生日
It was my ninth birthday--
他和我妈刚结束第一轮
Him and my mom had just finished round one of
喝酒  嘿咻  痛打杰罗姆
boozing, boning, beating up Jerome,
打算休息一下
and were deciding to take a little break.
总之...
Anyway...
我在拖车外面  你当时也在
I was outside the trailer, and you were there.
你说
And you said,
"哭什么  杰罗姆"
"Why are you crying, Jerome?"
"今天是我生日
"It's my birthday.
我妈妈和蛇舞男却打我"
And my mom and the snake guy are beating me."
然后你说
And then you said,
"这世界不关心你
"This world doesn't care about you
或其他任何人  杰罗姆
"or anyone else, Jerome.
你最好早点明白"
Better to realize that now."
再没说别的
And that was it.
你看  有个人  爸爸
You see, there's this guy, Dad.
他相信我
He believes in me.
他觉得我能成为巨星
He thinks I'm gonna be a star.
而今晚  哥谭所有人都会看清这点
And, tonight, all of Gotham will see that, too.
除了你
Except for you.
因为那时你已经  死了
'Cause you'll be, you know, dead.
杰罗姆
Jerome...
这就到你说你有多抱歉的部分了吗
Is this the part where you say how sorry you are?
说你该相信我的
How you should have believed in me,
说现在重新开始还不晚
how it's not too late to start again?
告诉你  爸爸  已经太晚了
News flash, Dad: it's too late.
你不必这么做
You don't have to do this.
不
No.
我确定我需要
I'm pretty sure I do.
我是个坏父亲  但我爱你
I was a bad father, but I did love you.
为这杀了我...
To kill me for that...
那不是我要杀你的原因
That's not why I'm gonna kill you.
阿卡姆精神病院的蓝图
Plans to Arkham Asylum.
看看这些
Look at these.
你和你疯儿子之间的信件
Letters between you and your troubled son.
初看很单纯  但是戈登警探
Innocent at first glance, but Detective Gordon--
你记得他  对吧
you remember him, right?--
他会感到上面疙疙瘩瘩的
he'll feel little bumps.
用盲文写下的秘密信息
A secret message written in Braille
是你和你儿子  在谈论我的逃脱
between you and your son, discussing my escape.
最后  是迷晕看护人的昏睡瓦斯
Finally, the knockout gas used to disable the orderlies.
因为你看  爸爸
'Cause, you see, Dad,
这个我跟你说的人
this guy I was telling you about,
是他帮我从阿卡姆越狱的
he's the one who broke me out of Arkham.
他不想让别人知道是他干的
He doesn't want anyone to know about that.
这是当然了  所以
Obviously. So...
警察会找到这些信件
the police will find these letters,
然后他们会想
and they'll think,
这瞎眼老傻瓜真是爱他儿子
"The blind old fool really loved his son.
多好的父亲
What a wonderful father."
屋里所有人眼中都会饱含泪水
There won't be a dry eye in the house.
他们绝不会相信的
They'll never believe it.
他们当然会  警察可蠢了
Sure, they will. Cops are dumb.
这里什么吃的都没有
There's nothing to eat in this dump.
赶紧结束了走吧
Finish up and let's go.
很遗憾你看不到我重要的一夜了  爸爸
Sorry you're gonna miss my big night, Dad.
不过  你是个灵媒
But, hey, you're psychic.
那么  告诉我
So, tell me,
我会杀你吗
do I kill?
你
You...
将成为哥谭的诅咒
will be a curse upon Gotham.
一想到你  孩子们就会
Children will wake from sleeps screaming
惊叫着从梦中醒来
at the thought of you.
你留下的
Your legacy
只有死亡和疯狂
will be death and madness.
那就
Well...
替我向妈妈问好吧
say hi to Mom for me.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
西瑟罗先生  我是戈登警探
Mr. Cicero, it's Detective Gordon.
我们要和你谈谈你儿子的事
We need to speak with you about your son.
西瑟罗先生
Mr. Cicero?
Mr. Cicero?!
哈维  他们从窗户跑了
Harvey, window!
哈维
Harvey?
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
老朋友啊
Old pal.
瓦斯效力可真厉害呢
That gas sure packs a wallop, huh?
真是可爱
That's cute.
我感觉你很愤怒
I'm sensing anger.
你杀了莎拉·艾森
You killed Sarah Essen.
我要杀了你
Now I'm gonna kill you.
别开枪
Don't shoot him.
来点皮肉伤怎么样
How about a little flesh wound?
不不
No, no.
我来
My dibs.
这就是浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
我们不是说好的吗  布鲁斯少爷
We had a deal, didn't we, Master Bruce?
你要恢复正常的生活方式
Part of which was you resume your normal lifestyle.
你父母曾是儿童医院的资助者
Your parents were both patrons to the Children's Hospital.
因此你也是资助者
Therefore, it makes you a patron.
而且
Besides...
会有魔术师哦
there's gonna be a magician.
你不是喜欢魔术师吗
And you like magicians, don't you?
不喜欢
No, I don't.
我讨厌魔术师
I hate magicians.
记得我说过要做个正常人吗
You know what I said about being normal?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我是莱·汤普金斯
I'm Lee Thompkins.
我是詹姆斯·戈登的同事
I work with James Gordon.
他提起过你  我看见你就想...
He's mentioned you, and I saw you and thought...
当然  非常高兴认识你
Of course. It's very nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
这是我的监护人阿尔弗雷德·潘尼沃斯
This is my guardian, Alfred Pennyworth.
十分荣幸
It's an absolute pleasure.
谢谢
Thank you.
警局遇袭后
How is Detective Gordon doing
戈登警探怎么样了
since the attack on the precinct?
我一直想打电话给他
I was thinking I should call him.
他会感激的
He'd appreciate that.
我给你拿点喝的吧
Can I get you something to drink?
水就行了  谢谢
Uh, just water. Thank you.
我听说一会儿会有魔术表演
So... I hear there's gonna be a magician.
你好  塞琳娜
Hello, Selina.
没想到能在这里遇见你
I-I didn't expect to see you here.
如果你要偷东西
Well, you want to steal stuff,
有钱人去哪  你也就跟去哪了
it helps to go where the rich people are.
你知道这是为儿童医院举办的慈善晚会吧
You do know this is a benefit for Children's Hospital?
所以呢
So?
所以这些人是为行善而来
So these people are here for a good cause.
我吃东西也是行善
Me eating is a good cause.
还有  我不是也为你偷过东西吗
Besides, didn't I steal something for you, once?
塞琳娜  那不同
Selina, that was different.
好吧
Right.
还顺利吗
How'd that go?
你打开那人的保险柜了吗
You get into that guy's safe?
打开了
Yes.
但结果跟我想的不太一样
Though things didn't turn out quite like I planned.
那之后发生了很多事
A lot's happened since then.
阿尔弗雷德说稍后有魔术表演
Alfred says there's gonna be a magician.
我在工作
I'm working.
而且我讨厌魔术
And I hate magicians.
回见  布鲁斯
See you around, Bruce.
想分享一下你的计划吗
So you want to share your plan?
记不记得我曾告诉你
Remember I told you
我能预言人们真正想要什么
I could divine the thing a person truly wants?
哥谭需要的是一个英雄
What Gotham wants is a hero.
而今晚
And tonight...
我就给他们一个英雄
I'm going to give them one.
走吧
Shall we?
杰罗姆和塔比先走了
Jerome and Tabby went on ahead.
披风真漂亮
Great cape.
谢谢你们愿意这么临时来替演
Thank you for filling in on such short notice.
但你怎么知道我们的魔术师退出了呢
But how did you hear our magician dropped out,
你叫...
Mr...?
鲁道夫
Rodolfo.
这就是  魔术嘛
Well, you know, magic.
我不会用到那个
Oh, I won't be needing that.
-说说嘛  -抱歉  真没什么神秘的
- Come on. - I'm sorry, but really, there is no mystery.
塔比莎  你见过凯恩副市长了吗
Tabitha, have you met Deputy Mayor Kane?
哈里森  这是我的塔比莎
Harrison, this is my Tabitha.
很高兴认识你
Ah, nice to meet you.
麻烦你转告你哥哥一声
Uh, and could you please tell your brother
人们看到一个从天而降的帅气富豪
that when a handsome billionaire appears out of nowhere,
都会心生好奇
people get curious.
他哪来的
Where'd he come from?
他钱是怎么赚的
How'd he make his money?
他在跟谁约会
Who's he dating?
我打探不出点什么消息
My wife would kill me if I don't get something--
我妻子肯定不饶我
a-a tidbit.
他在床上可生猛了
He's a monster in the sack.
你有詹姆斯市长的消息吗
Do you have any news of Mayor James?
没有
No.
真是奇了怪了
No, it's a real mystery.
我们不知道他在哪
We don't know where he is.
真是有趣
How intriguing.
哈里森  介意回避下吗  我们说点家事
Harrison, would you mind? A little family business.
当然  盖勒文小姐
Of course. Ms. Galavant.
一切就绪
Everything's ready.
回家见
See you at home.
你是怎么从皇家海军陆战队队员
So, uh, how do you go from being in the Royal Marines
变成管家的
to a butler?
说真的  干久了会有些枯燥
Well, it's a bit tedious, really, after a while.
全球四处高空跳伞到一个又一个危险地区
You know, parachuting into one global hot spot after another.
军阀出重金要取你人头
Warlords putting ridiculous bounties on your head.
真的会有些无聊
Gets a bit boring, really.
你的故事好精彩
You have amazing stories.
有那么一两个精彩的吧
Yeah, well, you know, one or two.
我晚上一般不休息
You know, I don't really get nights off,
但你要是哪晚有空来韦恩庄园
but if ever you'd like to pop by Wayne Manor
吃晚饭什么的  我
for dinner one evening, I...
谢谢你的好意  潘尼沃斯先生
Oh, that's very kind of you, Mr. Pennyworth, but...
别
No.
阿尔弗雷德  叫我阿尔弗雷德
Alfred. Please. Alfred.
阿尔弗雷德  谢谢你的好意  但是
Alfred. That's very kind of you, but...
虽说如此  但休息一晚也未尝不可
Now, having said that, I don't see why I can't take a night off,
我刚好认识
and I... I happen to know
谢兹帕奈斯餐厅的主厨
the head chef at Chez Parnes.
恐怕
Well, I-I'm afraid I...
你刚说谢兹帕奈斯吗
Did you say Chez Parnes?
我一直想去那里吃饭
I've been trying to eat there for quite some time.
你的眼睛美极了
You have the most beautiful eyes.
谢谢你
Okay, well, thank you,
但是
but, uh...
阿尔弗雷德  我想走了
Alfred, I'd like to leave.
好吧
Yeah, um...
汤普金斯医生的水呢
What about Dr. Thompkins' water?
而且  你要错过魔术了
And, of course, you're gonna miss the magician.
抱歉  我忘帮你拿水了
Sorry, I must have forgotten your water.
阿尔弗雷德  我真想走了
Alfred, I still want to leave.
你感觉不舒服吗
Are you not feeling well?
不  他好着呢  非常好
Oh, n-no, he's-he's absolutely fine. He's fine.
要不你去吧台那边看看吧
Why don't you just pop off to the bar,
布鲁斯少爷  然后...
Master Bruce, and...
表演马上要开始了
show's about to start.
时间到了吗
Is it time?
我今晚要担任主持人
I roped myself into emcee duties for the night.
希望你们能留下来看演出
I hope you'll stay for the show.
我绝不会错过的
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
怎么了
What?
晚上好
Good evening.
我是莱·汤普金斯医生
I'm Dr. Lee Thompkins.
这五年来
For the past five years,
我有幸能在儿童医院工作
I've had the honor of being part of the Children's Hospital.
谢谢你们的资助
Thank you for your support.
也感谢大家今晚能够出席
And thank you so much for coming out tonight.
这几年来  我们都会请魔术师
Over the years, we've had magicians
为孩子们进行表演
come and entertain our children.
今晚  我们为大家请来了其中一位魔术师
And so tonight, we have one of the magicians here for you.
闲话少说
Without further ado,
容我为大家介绍
please allow me to present to you
魔术大师鲁道夫
the Great Rodolfo.
女士们先生们  晚上好
Greetings, ladies and germs!
我是魔术大师鲁道夫
I am indeed the Great Rodolfo.
这位是我可爱的助手
Please ogle my lovely assistant.
我的第一个表演需要一名志愿者
For my first act, I'll require a volunteer.
我看看
Let me see.
点兵点将
Duck, duck,
点兵点将点兵点将...
duck, duck, duck, duck, duck...
就是你
goose!
去吧  布鲁斯少爷
Go on, Master Bruce.
给点面子
Be a sport.
别让女士久等
Don't keep the lady waiting.
好吧
Fine.
你好  年轻人
Hello, young man.
请问
Does this
这位帅气的先生叫什么
handsome gentleman have a name?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
Bruce!
布鲁斯  这一点都不会疼
Well, Bruce, this won't hurt a bit.
这里有医生吗
Is there a doctor in the house?
不...不好意思...
No, just... Excuse...
等等  等等
Just wait! Wait!
等一会儿
Wait one second!
回家去吧
Go home.
我没事
I'm fine.
你从昨天晚上起就在忙活
You've been running this since last night,
还被喷了一脸毒气  回家吧
and you got a face full of that gas. Go home.
你回家吗
You going home?
我猜就是
I didn't think so.
也许我是该回去睡一觉
Maybe I will go get some sleep.
是吗  好主意
Yeah? Good idea.
但总算有进展  是吧
But we got somewhere, right?
至少我们现在知道是谁帮杰罗姆逃出阿卡姆了
At least now we know who broke Jerome out of Arkham.
是啊  独居的瞎眼疯老头
Yeah. Crazy old blind man that lived alone.
聪明的瞎眼疯老头
The clever crazy old blind man.
如果是他父亲帮他越了狱  杰罗姆为什么杀他
If his father broke him out, why'd Jerome kill him, huh?
大概自从你把他送去阿卡姆
He was probably playing this maniac shtick
他就在谋划干这疯狂事了
since you sent him away.
他就是个孩子
He was just a kid.
这世上每个混蛋曾经都是个孩子
Every evil bastard in the world was just a kid once.
是啊
Yeah.
但我不认为是他父亲帮他越狱的
But I don't think it was his father that broke him out.
好吧
Well, cool.
又回到起点了
Back to square one.
好吧  我去睡会儿
All right, I will go and get some sleep.
对了
For the record,
我认识艾森比你久多了
I knew Essen a hell of a lot longer than you.
她救过我无数次
She saved my ass hundreds of times.
你真的该回家了
You really should go home.
我们明天一早就去找企鹅
First thing tomorrow, we'll go see Penguin.
你说得对
You're right.
他街上有耳目
He's got his ears on the street.
吉姆
Jim.
算了
Never mind.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
跟他们挥挥手
Give 'em a wave.
有人说布鲁斯人格分裂呢
Some people say Bruce has a split personality.
很不错  布鲁斯少爷
Very good, Master Bruce.
下一个魔术
For my next illusion,
我想请尊敬的副市长上台来
I'd like to call to the stage esteemed Deputy Mayor
有请哈里森·凯恩
Harrison Kane.
你觉得他俩眼熟吗
Is there something familiar to you about those two?
天呐
Oh, my God.
小莱  我正要
Lee, I was just...
吉姆  是芭芭拉
Jim, it's Barbara.
她也在这儿  我觉得杰罗姆可能也...
She's here. And-and I think maybe Jerome...
对了  没有人
By the way, nobody here...
能活着出去
is getting out alive.
好了  布鲁斯少爷  该走了
Right, Master Bruce, time to leave.
塞琳娜
Selina!
布鲁斯
Bruce!
你
You!
怎么回事
What's going on?
人质危机
Hostage situation.
魔术师刚刚杀了副市长
The magician just killed the deputy mayor.
是杰罗姆·瓦勒斯卡
It's Jerome Valeska,
就是杀死艾森局长的那个人
the same man that killed Commissioner Essen.
这里谁负责
Who's in charge here?
看来是你了
I guess you are.
小莱
Lee.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
-我一直在  -抱歉了  吉姆
- I've been trying to... - Sorry, Jimbo.
只是我啦
It's just little old me.
杰罗姆
Jerome.
你在外面吗
Are you outside?
你就在外面  是吧
You are, aren't you?
天呐
Oh, goody!
我发誓  你敢伤害她
I swear to God, if you've hurt her...
放松  詹姆斯
Breathe, James.
我还没碰你漂亮女朋友的一根汗毛呢
I haven't touched a hair on your girlfriend's pretty head.
自己看吧
See for yourself.
这可是直播电视节目啊
This is live television after all.
信号刚刚恢复
The feed just came back.
你个婊子养的
You son of a bitch.
这是实话  但不是重点
True, but not the point.
我们谈谈我想要什么吧
Hey, let's talk about what I want.
失陪
Excuse me.
四千七百万  一架直升机  不用说
$47 million, a helicopter, obviously,
我留在张氏干洗店的衣服
the dry cleaning I left at Mr. Chang's--
小心哦  那人可狡诈了
be careful, the man is a crook--
还有什么呢  小马吧
and, mm, I don't know, a pony.
给你十分钟  否则我就开始杀人
You got ten minutes, or I start killing people.
记住  这是直播
Remember, this is being broadcast
哥谭千家万户都看得到
to every home in Gotham, so, you know,
别搞出人命哦  再见
don't let people die. Bye.
挺顺利的啊
I think that went well.
够了
Enough!
收起你可悲的表演滚蛋吧
You need to pack up your pathetic little sideshow and leave.
是嘛
Is that right?
或许我不该替所有哥谭市民妄下断言
It may be presumptuous to speak for all the citizens of Gotham.
但我们受够你了
But we are sick of you!
你这个渺小恶毒的人
You're a small,vicious man
只想求关注  真可悲
with a pathetic need for attention.
够了
Enough, man.
真是够了
For God's sakes, enough.
我很想知道你有什么筹码  这位先生
I'm curious what your leverage is here, Mr...?
西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan.
好吧  西奥·盖勒文先生
Well, Mr. Theo Galavan,
你要是不坐下
if you don't sit down,
我就要打死你了
uh, I'm going to shoot you.
爆头
In the face.
我知道你心底还有些残存的人性
I know there is some human decency left in you.
如果你想要劫持人质  就劫我吧
If you need to take a hostage, take me.
让这些人回到家人身边
But let these people go home to their families,
回到孩子身边
to their children.
真无聊
Boring.
是吧
Right?
带上人  我们进去
Get your men. We're going in.
我走这条路溜进派对
I used this to sneak into the party.
幸好那些白痴不知道
We're lucky those dummies didn't know about it.
等等
Wait.
-我们就出去了  -等等
- We're almost outside. - Wait.
我得回去
I have to go back.
你疯了吗  那人在杀人啊
Are you crazy? That guy was killing people!
是啊  阿尔弗雷德还在那儿呢
Yes, and Alfred's back there.
我不会回去的
I'm not going back.
我没指望你会
I don't expect you to.
塞琳娜
Selina...
我挺想你的
I miss you.
我只想告诉你这个
I just wanted to say that.
你敢抗命  我可以开了你
You're refusing a direct order? I could have your stripes.
那疯子杀了局长
That maniac killed the commissioner.
我不能让他杀我手下  我们没做好这种准备
Not my men. We're not equipped for this.
好吧  我自己去
Fine. I'll go it alone.
别动
Hold very still.
我不敢看
I can't look.
谁告诉我结果如何
Someone tell me how it turns out.
该死
Damn!
转过去
Turn around.
鼓掌啊
Well, clap!
小莱  吉姆怎么样了
So, Lee, how's Jim doing?
希望他没为艾森的死
I hope he's not blaming himself
责备自己
for this whole Essen being killed thing.
你真是个疯婊子
You are one crazy bitch.
真没礼貌
So rude.
我要做个预测
You know, I'm gonna... I'm gonna make a prediction.
不到一年  我和吉姆就会复合
Within a year, Jim and I will be back together.
想知道为什么吗
Want to know why?
因为我们是一样的
Because we're both the same.
我们都有阴暗面
We both have a dark side.
有一天  我们会给孙辈讲述
And one day, we will tell our grandchildren
当年有个小妖精差点拆散了我们
about how this man-eating harpy almost tore us apart!
但最终  爱战胜了一切
But in the end, love conquered all.
-你  -抱歉  什么
- You... - I'm sorry. What's that?
还没到十分钟  我得给你买块表了
Hasn't been ten minutes. I need to buy you a watch.
好了
Well...
该选出今晚的首位受害人了
I think it's time for tonight's first official victim,
你们都熟悉喜欢的  可怜的小富翁
you all know and love, poor rich boy,
父母被杀害于小巷中  我最喜欢的志愿者
parents murdered in an alley, and my favorite volunteer.
布鲁斯·韦恩哪去了
Where is... Bruce Wayne?!
我也是个孤儿呢  布鲁斯
You know I'm an orphan, too, Bruce?
不过是我杀了自己的双亲
I killed my parents though.
你躲在哪呢
Where are you hiding?
布鲁斯
Bruce!
你在哪呢
Where are you, buddy?
杀了他的管家
Kill his butler.
上来  走  管家
Come on, move it, butler.
好了
All right.
最后机会  布鲁斯
Last chance, Bruce,
这里就要管家脑浆四溅了
but it's about to get very butler brainy out here.
戈登警探
D-Detective Gordon.
他要杀阿尔弗雷德  我得去救他
He's going to kill Alfred. I have to help him.
布鲁斯
Brucey!
不  那正中他下怀
No. It's you he wants.
布鲁斯  他就想要你
Bruce, just wants you.
我不能允许他伤害阿尔弗雷德
I will not let him hurt Alfred.
我无聊了  打死管家
I'm bored. Shoot the butler.
住手
Stop!
你出来干什么  布鲁斯
What the bloody hell are you doing, Bruce?
我衣服里有枪
There's a gun in my jacket.
戈登警探在帘子后面
Detective Gordon's behind the curtain.
我们开始吧
Let's get this started, huh?
你去帘子后面看看
You, check behind the curtain;
确保没人打扰我们
make sure no one's playing silly buggers.
放下刀
Drop the knife!
我打不中
I don't have a clean shot!
冷静  布鲁斯
Stay calm, Bruce.
看来我们陷入困境了
Seems like we got ourselves a pickle.
怎么办  小布鲁斯
What do you say, Brucey boy?
想提高收视率吗
Want to boost our ratings, huh?
笑一个
Smile.
我说  够了
I said, enough!
我知道
I know, I know.
跟我们彩排的不一样
This is not what we rehearsed.
抱歉了  杰罗姆
I'm so sorry, Jerome.
你真的很有才华
You have real talent.
但现在呢
But now, you see,
剧情更精彩了
the plot thickens.
英雄上场了
Enter the hero.
你说
You said...
我会成为...
I was gonna be...
吉姆  拦住她
Jim! Stop her!
小马吧
...A pony.
这种人根本不想成就什么
See, someone like that has no interest in building things.
他不属于传统
He's not part of a tradition.
只是专为混乱而混乱
It's chaos for chaos sake.
或许我该换换笑声
Perhaps I could use a new laugh.
哥们
Dude!
我佩服啊
Color me impressed.
如果我闭上眼睛
You know, if I close my eyes,
还能看到你举着菲什雨伞的样子
I can still see you holding Fish's umbrella.
是  穆尼女士
"Yes, Ms. Mooney.
不  穆尼女士  都听您的  穆尼女士
"No, Ms. Mooney. Whatever you say, Ms. Mooney.
您的假发太合适了  穆尼女士
That wig looks great on you, Ms. Mooney."
真的  咸鱼翻身了
Seriously, the worm has turned.
布洛克警探
Detective Bullock.
听说你重回警队了
I heard you rejoined the force.
我真开心啊
I am so happy.
但你是不是错过精彩了呢
But aren't you missing all of the excitement?
是啊  我收到消息时太迟了
Yeah, I got the word too late.
而且  我想跟你聊聊
Besides, I want to talk to you.
当然
Of course.
我一向乐意帮忙
Always happy to help.
街面上有传言说
See, there's talk on the street
吉姆·戈登帮了你个忙
that Jim Gordon did a favor for you,
去收了笔账  结果闹出人命
collected a debt, and the guy ended up dead.
传言而已
Rumors.
传言
不过嘛  俗话说空穴来风
Well, then again, where there's smoke...
吉姆不用担心
Jim shouldn't worry about that.
他和我是好朋友
He and I are good friends.
问题就在这里  奥斯瓦尔德
Well, see, that's the problem, Oswald;
我觉得他的确担心
I think he is worried.
因为今天出了点事
Because something happened today,
你显然是他该求助的人
and you were the obvious person to come to.
而我能感到吉姆不太愿意来
And I sensed Jim was a little reluctant to come down here.
我说了  他不必担心
Like I said, he shouldn't worry.
只要你们还是朋友就行
As long as you two remain friends.
是啊
Exactly.
我很想把你揪出去
I got half a mind to take you outside
用垃圾箱把你揍成肉饼
and beat you senseless with a garbage can.
或许改日吧
Maybe some other time.
随你怎么自封
Call yourself whatever you want, man!
哥谭之王
The King of Gotham.
但在我看来  你永远是那个举伞的
But, to me, you'll always be that little umbrella boy.
你敢找吉姆·戈登的麻烦  就是找我的麻烦
And if you come after jim Gordon, you got to come after me.
菲什的事我还没跟你算呢
And I still owe you for Fish.
不过  说真的  这地方真不赖
But, seriously, this place is amazing.
再给我倒杯酒
Get me another drink!
你刚刚很勇敢
You were very brave.
你帮忙救了这里所有人
You helped save the lives of everyone in here.
你父母会为你自豪的
Your parents, they would've been proud.
是啊
That they would've been.
但我让你做了这样的傻事
They also would've given me the sack
他们还会解雇了我
for letting you do something so idiotic.
是我们齐心合力
It was all of us.
我们是一个团队
We were a team.
是啊  的确
Yeah. I guess we were.
他没事吧
Is he okay?
没事  但我还是希望
Fine. Though I'd still like him
他去医院看看
to get checked out at the hospital.
芭芭拉下手不轻
Barbara gave him quite a knock.
有她的消息吗
Any word on her?
没有  她用舞台的活板门逃了
No, she went through a trapdoor in the stage.
他们肯定本就打算用那个逃跑的
They must have always been planning to use that as their exit.
别担心  我们会找到她的
Don't worry. We'll find her.
盖勒文先生
Uh, Mr. Galavan, sir.
阿尔弗雷德·潘尼沃斯
Alfred Pennyworth.
我想感谢你救了
I'd just like to thank you for saving
韦恩少爷的命
young Master Wayne's life.
如果我能为你做什么  先生
If there's anything I can ever do for you, sir...
还有我
Or I.
我不过是做了任何一位哥谭市民都会做的
I really just did what any citizen of Gotham would have done.
是那样就好了
I wish that were true.
吉姆·戈登
Jim Gordon.
西奥
Theo.
如果你需要什么帮助  尽管打给我
Well, if you ever need anything, please, call.
我们都是一起的  是吧
We're all in this together, right?
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
我得赶紧送这位年轻人回家了
Right, well, I suppose I better be getting this young man home.
今晚比本来设想的
It's been much more of an exciting evening
要刺激多了
than originally planned.
我一向不喜欢魔术师
I never did like magicians.
晚安
Good night.
认识你很高兴  汤普金斯医生
It was very nice meeting you, Dr. Thompkins.
我也是  布鲁斯
And you, Bruce.
好好睡一晚  又会精神焕发了
Good night's sleep, you'll be right as roses.
希望我们很快还能再见到你
I do hope we get to see you again soon.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿尔弗雷德  走吧
Alfred.
你真没事吗
Sure you're okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
亲一个
Kiss me?
-吉姆  -亲一个嘛
- Jim... - Kiss me.
-真烦人  -阿尔弗雷德
- Oh, bugger. - Alfred.
-你早知道吧  -我不知道  阿尔弗雷德
- You knew, didn't you? - I didn't know, Alfred.
你就知道  你有意让我自己丢人现眼
You did. You let me make a right mug of me-self.
阿尔弗雷德  我真不知道
Alfred, I had no idea.
-你就知道  -我不知道
- You did. - I didn't know.
我也不知道啊
Well, I didn't know.
虽然有哥谭市警局到场
Despite the presence of the GCPD,
却是西奥·盖勒文  才刚到哥谭
it was billionaire Theo Galavan-- newly arrived in Gotham
就已名声鹊起的亿万富翁
but already making his name--
站出来抵抗逃狱的疯子
who stood up to the escaped lunatic.
我是英雄了吗
Am I a hero?
看来是的
Apparently.
今晚  哥谭人民说出了"够了"
I think tonight, the people of Gotham have said, "Enough."
暴君的统治结束了
the reign of tyranny is over.
现在好玩的才开始
Now the real fun begins.
可怜的杰罗姆
Poor Jerome.
是啊  真可惜
Yes, very sad.
如此引人瞩目  但太局限性了
Such a compelling character. But limited, you know?
他本来也混不长的
He was never gonna last long.
这未必
I don't know about that.
他挺有调调的
The kid had a way about him.
可怜的宝贝
Oh, poor baby,
你撞肿了吗
did you get a bump?
杀人犯  杰罗姆·瓦勒斯卡  已死亡
...the killer, Jerome Valeska, is dead,
他凶残的行为给哥谭留下了深刻印象
his murderous escapades left a deep impression on Gotham.
没有人能活着出去
Nobody here is getting out alive.
借过
Coming through.
你将成为哥谭的诅咒
You will be a curse upon Gotham.
一想到你  孩子们就会
Children will wake from sleep screaming
惊叫着从梦中醒来
at the thought of you.
你留下的  只有死亡和疯狂
Your legacy will be death and madness.